One of the biggest learnings we've had
when we started data dog was that
there's one lie customers will tell you
which is if your system has a smart to
detect issues, I prefer you to give me
the false positives and then I'll decide
whether they're right or not. And that's
a lie. The reality of it is that you
send two false positives to people in a
row and then they turn you off forever.
Voice will be the future of the digital
interactions of how you interact with
interfaces of the digital world and it
can carry so much more emotion so much
understanding than text and the plethora
of use cases is widened. We actually
think that there will be one or two new
model breakthroughs that are required in
the audio space to really get it to
another level. who just went out and and
spoke to hundreds maybe even thousands
of people try and understand like what
is video you know why do people make
video who's not making video but wants
to make video and I think that was one
the advantage we have being like very
young and being very naive is that you
can really approach a space with zero
baggage right
[Music]
>> hi there Simon Maple here from the AI
native dev and on today's episode we're
going to have a quick look back at a
number of episodes where We see some of
the leading companies in AI start
building their own platforms and in some
cases building their own models to
improve some of the products that
they're actually building. Uh we're
going to start off with the data dog CEO
Olivier Pomel and his discussion with
Guy Pjani. And as part of that with
there was there was a part of that
discussion whereby uh Olivier talked
about how they uh they flood essentially
flood the LLM with a bunch of of um of
of work that that essentially logic that
assesses whether their answers are
trustworthy. Um and essentially LMS will
always answer whether that's right or
whether it's wrong. So it's really
really important to to provide the uh
the user with an amount of confidence
and and that's exactly what uh data dog
did. So really really interesting about
how they use that almost like a a level
of trustworthiness before providing that
information to the the end user.
>> I guess the first thing I want to talk
about a little bit is sort of trusting
the insights from these tools. Right. So
you mentioned you know bits and in
general there's a lot of uh maybe like
an intrinsic understanding that that is
sort of you know easy to gro around the
fact that observability deals with like
know vast amounts of data and you know
AI is amazing at data. It can look at
all these things and now it can read the
lines and kind of make sense of them and
give you whatever it is the root cause
analysis or even like choose when to
wake you up at night. Uh but as uh we've
just discussed with some snowboarding
examples uh it also doesn't always get
it right I guess. H how do you first
maybe what's your sort of sense of the
current accuracy level of of detecting
these things and kind of you know giving
you the correct answer and and what's
the what's the appetite for
experimentation in this domain amidst uh
amidst users like are they uh accepting
shall we say of uh of mistakes you know
do they uh do they expect perfection
>> yeah I think uh so I'll start with one
of the biggest learnings we've had when
we uh started data dog was that there's
one lie customers will tell you you know
which is uh if your system has a smarts
to detect issues um I prefer you to give
me the false positives and then I'll
decide whether they're right or not and
that's a lie. Uh the reality of it is
that you send um two false positives to
people in a row and then they turn you
off forever. Um there's very little
appetite to chase down uh the wrong path
because of a machine that told you so.
Uh people will do it because of a human
corker but they won't they won't do it
because of a machine. And so the bar for
u precision needs to be very very high
on the on anything that has to that
relates to observability.
Um and the the good news is that you
know I would say three four years ago um
being uh completely right about uh root
cause most of the time was science
fiction u and I think now it's
definitely within reach um we see it in
the way you know what we've been
developing we see it in the the
progression of the evaluations for that
and you know as you know you know you've
been building on AI too so you know
evaluations the hardest part
>> there's there uh it's it's a joy and a
nightmare to sort of be building with
the predictability but uh you definitely
sort of see the progress and the uh the
power that comes in.
>> Yes. And we see you know we see we see
actually very good progress there and we
can clearly see on the horizon at the
moment where the uh the technology is
good enough to be put into the hands of
customers on in in a large amount large
number of situations. Um so that's sort
of where we are but yes the bar needs to
be super high. One thing we found
interestingly is that uh the bar is a
little bit lower in some uh related
areas such as security. Um I think uh
users and customers are more willing um
to uh take a bet on automated decisions
or automated uh notifications for
security than they are for operations.
And I think the reason for that is that
the the riskreward is a little bit
different. I think it's uh it's okay um
to uh crash a workload if you uh avoid a
security incident. Uh whereas it's less
okay to crash a workload to avoid
crashing the workload.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's sort of a
little bit of running. It's really
interesting though because security
um well first of all like the security
my experience at sneak is actually like
very similar in terms of the false
positive false negative uh element
right. It starts off by sort of saying
find all the issues. If you're not sure,
tell me about it. I want to know. The
reality is that's actually the primary
thing they would sort of feel. Uh they
don't tell you. But it's interesting
though your comment about uh identifying
flaws uh or like maybe having more
tolerance around sort of alerts because
um to an extent identifying whether
something is or isn't uh uh an attempted
breach is also something that's um kind
of less less definitive I guess uh on
it. So maybe just people have lower
expectations. they just don't expect
anyone including kind of human assessors
to to be able to spot uh what is uh what
is correct or or is not correct and so
it could be could be the impact or it
could just be sort of the expectation of
uh the art of the possible
>> yeah also just to level set what we
discussed I think when you compare
what's happening in operations and
security um to uh what is happening in
other areas of AI like these are hard
problems to solve you know when we think
about we think about um self-driving
cars for example which are just about
working now. Um what uh what these do
are you know what pretty much any human
over the age of 16 can can do uh u
without even thinking about it. Yeah.
Whereas when we think of the the
incidents, you know, at least the ones
we've had and the ones we've seen our
customers have, like it takes large
teams of very qualified people and PhDs,
you know, and a lot of a lot of time to
try and understand what's going on and
and you know, sometimes weeks after the
after the incident, you're still
thinking about them and still working
through them and understanding exactly
what happened. Uh so these are really
hard problems to solve.
>> Yeah. No, I agree. And I guess on top of
that there's a notion of understanding
the application itself right um so I
guess so so maybe two questions coming
out of that one is like trust is is uh
is imperative right people want they
they have low tolerance for mistakes on
it but the systems are as you've also
mentioned you know not predictable and
so uh I guess one question is can they
find it but even even if they could find
it it doesn't mean they can find it
again if given the exact same uh set of
information so so I guess how do you how
do you think about solving it is the
solution sort of the the copilot world
and leaning into that until it's good
enough. Is it about sort of narrow
slices? Is there a different lens? Like
how do you how do you still make
progress you know while you know you
don't have uh perfection you have
expectation of perfection and and the
systems don't I guess don't yet allow
they're getting close but there's sort
of a line of sight for perfection but I
don't think it's present.
>> Yes I think there's two issues there. is
what's the right form factor for the
customers to interact with it the right
way and that's where you you think about
you know is it better to have a copilot
or is it bigger better to have an agent
that does things on its own uh should it
be you know do you want to interact with
it vocally do you want a button do you
want like how do you what does that look
like and that's a big question there
like there's a real um UI question but
also you know the UI really sets up the
expectations from the from the the end
user so there's a
a big thing there and I think we're
still as an industry we're still
figuring out what works. What's pretty
clear is that the the chat interface uh
was a great start. You know, it was it
opens everyone's imagination, but it's
not the be all end all. I think most of
the AI based functionality is not going
to work from a chat interface in the in
the long run.
The second question is how do you build
uh or how do you enter
um the the market with a solution that
uh shows confidence um and or or builds
confidence with the end user and I think
for that the I mean you can get higher
precision by having lower recall uh and
you want to start in a maybe with corner
cases maybe with some small subsection
of all the things you can all incidents
you could possibly
possibly solve, but focus on the ones
that have the uh the really really high
precisions first. Um now the challenge,
you know, with the naive approaches is
that the LLMs in particular are not good
at understanding when they know and what
they don't know. You know, they'll
always gladly answer and, you know,
might be wrong a lot of the time. So I
think a lot of the the technology that
we're building there is around
understanding when we're right, when
we're not right, when we have a super
super high chance of being right. Um so
we can actually volunteer guests and
maybe solve the issue directly for
customers as opposed to to not saying
anything. Um one advantage we have as a
company that's already used for
observability is that we can um choose
pick and choose basically the uh the the
use cases and the uh the issues uh for
which we're going to to um to uh uh
automatically uh take action. And so
that's what we're focusing focusing on
today.
>> Got it. Makes sense. So you're already
monitoring the whole thing and so you
can make a lot of attempts sort of see
where is it, what are the cases in which
you can reach a high confidence
conclusion of it and then kind of reach
in which definitely is a kind of an
incumbent advantage of of sort of
already being in place and already
seeing the data.
>> Exactly. And you know that's not a
choice that's so obvious. You don't have
that choice in in some other parts of
the industry. for example, for
self-driving cars, you know, you can't
say, you know, only going to take to to
make left turns, you know, and good at
them. Uh, I think the that's a luxury we
have in, you know,
>> right in that sort of breath. So, that
makes a lot of sense. So, I guess maybe
leading from this into the sort of the
world of uh of agents of it. So, you
know, you're in the spot, you look at
all the data, you sort of see the data
uh for the specific cases where you have
conclusions. How do you think about
actions? You know what is the these are
the insights maybe that you have higher
confidence. Do you see some that you
reach an like such high confidence that
you can even act on them? How do how do
you think about the agentic
um responses to this data the
non-passive version of observability uh
in in its stands today?
>> I think that's definitely the goal and
we we we see areas where we can we can
do it. I think the uh the the lowest
hanging fruits there are things such as
uh errors for example. So you have you
know you ship a new application uh and
you you have some 500s on the servers
you know and the you know that's pretty
clearly an error pretty clearly needs to
be remediated. It's usually not that
hard to generate the code that uh will
fix the errors. uh but then there's
quite a bit more more work involved into
getting that that code across and
validated and you know and and running
in production. So that's one area where
you can take action you know I would say
pretty automatically and pretty quickly
and that's definitely something we're
working on right now. There's a few
other areas. I mean, we um I think it's
uh luckily a few years ago, we we we
started building the ability to take
action for customers and so we built a
workflow automation product uh we built
functionality so customers could uh
could build applications and and that
automate the uh the way they run their
own operations uh internally. Um and
that's a big um departure from what we
had been doing for the first 10 years of
the company. The first 10 years we were
very careful about uh only receiving
data, never taking action, never
reaching back. And I think all of that
is is really coming to um to fruition
now that that you know we're trying to
close that loop and really automate
response for for users. I'm a firm
believer that um for AI to show its uh
its value, you need to automate action.
I think if you have to keep pestering
the humans to do things uh you're not
going to be successful.
>> The second conversation is really with
uh Matty Stenki uh from the CEO of 11
Labs and one of the things that um they
found was after trying a whole bunch of
open- source models, they didn't really
find that that level of of kind of like
dubbing was was sufficient enough using
those types of models. they had to build
their own and they talk really about how
their team progressed uh through uh you
know a number of different ways in
building their own much more expressive
way of dubbing uh various uh various
voices and things like that. So
wonderful wonderful session from uh
Matty on on the growth of 11 Labs. So
let's indeed maybe talk about the the
early days uh and and maybe the sort of
the technical breakthroughs, right? So I
I know and people like it's easy to find
when you write look for uh writeups
about 11 Labs kind of origin story uh
how you were uh frustrated with the uh
dubbing uh experience you and your
co-founder uh Peter, right? Yes. Um uh
of uh of Polish movies of it. I kind of
grew up in Israel. I'm I'm I'm familiar.
Israel fortunately has kind of embraced
that. Nobody's going to bother dubbing
to uh to Hebrew. not enough sort of
Hebrew speakers uh and therefore you
sort of see things in in English. But
dubbing in in Polish was underwhelming
uh and he wanted to fix that. But I
think you know that's sort of a a nice
succinct easy thing to say. Uh but from
there to actually kind of technically
execute that it's not one thing and I
know you you kind of had to break
through a bunch of walls maybe in those
months that you were exploring the
ideas. Um, I guess I'm curious what were
the sort of the core original
innovations or sort of breakthroughs or
even just problem spaces you had to to
do to to deliver on this hey we want to
do AI powered the dubbing
>> the um and you are right it's even even
even worse than just poor dubbing where
if you watch a foreign movie in Polish
you not only um usually you would have
dabbing with lower quality but you have
one voice narrating all the characters
so whether it's a male or a female voice
you have like one one one person
narrating everyone no emotions no
inonation they on purpose keep it even
flat so you can um infer yourself the
emotions on what's happening um and the
crazy thing is of course we knew it when
when we grew up but it's still happening
for majority of content today uh and and
something that we know will change as
the technology evolves so maybe like a a
quick quick background there so my my
co-ounder worked a lot through the years
and he is a brilliant researcher he
worked doing that at at at university
initially spending time on image space
then working Google on knowledger graph
uh so closer to the text space um and he
hasn't worked on audio but uh but a lot
of the ideas that that that we've seen
in those other sister fields or uh other
fields across AI were potentially
applicable in audio and we know that
this will be something that is possible
and fixable and on the other side from
from what I was seeing is that there's
no great product for the space to really
do anything with audio AI space and
very clear problem set of people that we
were outbounding to of like would it
actually help in your process when you
started the company
>> what was the sort of state-of-the-art
for audio at the time like three years
ago
>> what would have been like the best
product out there at the time
>> most most I mean there were some early
indications through 2022 of some open
source projects that were a bit better
but like most of the voice quality was
what we would experience of Alexa or
Siri right uh so uh like something that
you can immediately tell is a robot
>> that it's robotic Exactly. Um but we so
we started uh and and you know when we
when we speak about this this initial
problem we started actually with
building dubbing solution. So um in the
early 22 the first prototype we've built
was effectively a stitch up of few of
those different steps. So the first step
is understanding um the speechto text
part who is saying what and what they
are saying. Mhm.
>> Uh and already in that step the process
isn't perfect because most of the models
weren't able to detect um uh uh
different speakers or overlaps
accurately. Um the speech to text was
okay for English but the the the element
of of of when things are being said was
hard and the second was hard was the
time stamps of of like exactly knowing
when is when is it being said. So that
was the first the speech to text. So
it's it's more than just transcription
which maybe was a little bit more
evolved at least for English
>> but it's a lot more of that sort of
segregation of the conversation and the
time stamps of it.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. And that's where
where um where we've seen already the
gaps that we might need to address. Um
so so speech speech texture first one
and maybe just to give like wider
overview then you have the translation
part of changing from one language to
another. Well, of course in dubbing you
need to keep the length rightly the same
given you'll be dubbing uh uh u in the
other language. True in audio unless you
extend the video but that's that's
something that most platforms wouldn't
support. So there's the translation step
and then there's the last one which is
the texttospech step. Um so speech to
text we knew that there are some faults.
There's there were good open source
models for for the transcription side
like Nemo from Nvidia but uh but really
the other parts were were lacking and
where we spend a lot of time like okay
can we build that additional speaker
diorization to detect the speakers can
we build some better understanding of
time step and how we chunk that together
the translation of course something that
uh is a massive problem that we know we
won't be able to fix ourselves. So here
we would rely on anything best um that
exists at the at the time. Um
>> and this is three years ago is is pre-
chat GPT but it's not prel GPT2 is
around. Uh like were you already using
those types of technologies?
>> Exactly like 20 2022 like you could see
some of that momentum. So um both GPT2
there were like other just callable APIs
that we would try um and we try all of
them. Um and the truth is like already
then you had you know 80% of the quality
of the translation well and then it
really depended on the type of content.
If you had like a voiceover documentary
translation was pretty good.
>> Um the moment it started being like
short sentences with a lot of emotions
that when it would fall fall through but
we would use any external API or or um
or or starting to use the models which
is also good for us because it kind of
gave us the signal what's happening in
the field.
>> Yeah. And then the the third step text
to speech. Um here uh I think in the
very first prototypes we just used uh
whatever was was was best. Uh there's
the famous famous um one of the famous
paper for famous open source project for
some people in the field called Porto uh
which was which was incredible where you
could um effectively that the first uh
step change from those Siri Alexa voices
into something that sounds human. The
problem with that model was that it only
performed well on the very short
segments. So when you had it longer, it
would deteriorate, it wouldn't be
stable, you couldn't create that voice
stability over time. So we started
looking into like how we could
potentially modify it to to our own
setup uh using the the Tortoise as a
base. But that's early 2022. Yeah.
>> And and you're uh you're um my kind of
layman view a little bit think about it.
There's also the notion of capturing
emotion, right? transcription doesn't
capture emotions uh doing it. So you'd
have to somehow annotate that or maybe
the Polish background you sort of you
started way not expressing any any
emotions you know like like the dumpers
there uh right then and is that uh
>> that's correct. So like the main the
main thing like you want to capture in
that process of course is like what is
being said how it's being said and who
says it right and and um and the how I
mean hasn't been solved before um and
the way we thought about this in in
those early days uh in those early 2022
days it was could we effectively take
the original voice clone or reproduce
that well if we do it in a short enough
sample in that short enough sample there
will be enough of the emotions that we
and effectively take from the original
and then when we recreate that in the
other language that short sample will
carry some of that emotionality across.
Um but we've built this prototype it was
like this end to end dabbing with those
three steps. Um and it was it was okay.
It was like not perfect especially like
looking now at what's possible. Um and
we knew that all those components aren't
good enough to produce the dubbing
solution. Also, as you think about
dubbing, it's like combining those three
tech like three different technology
stacks which uh were underdeveloped at
the time. Um, and if you combine them,
it's it's and the sum of the parts
wasn't greater of of the parts. It was
still like just just just just good. Uh,
and at the same time, we were we were
starting to ask a lot of the potential
users, creators, like would you be
interested in in dubbing uh trying to
prototype based on our work? And it was
very clear quickly that the the quality
is slightly below where they would
actually be interested in like pushing
ahead um at the at the time we could
deliver. Um and then we took a step back
and that's kind of to your second part
of the question which was to be able to
solve this problem truly instead of
relying on the technologies that exist
what we really need to build is our own
models. So not rely on any of the the
ones that do exist for audio, but
actually go a step step deeper and try
to create our own starting with
texttospech model and voice voice
cloning or voice creation model to fix
that last step, right?
>> Which at the same time coincided with
understanding the pain point of like
when we outbounded about dubbing.
Dubbing was like, "Yes, dubbing is a
problem out there in the future, but
really if I could just do the voiceovers
more easily without my voice, if I could
correct and pre-process or post-process
and understand how the script can sound
or change the corrections after I've
done it, those will be so much more
immensely helpful." So, we had those two
very clear signals of like there's this
big other problem that is on the way to
solve what we set out with and then the
research isn't good enough. So, we
actually need to take a step back and
build our own right
>> our own models. We then talk with Victor
Ripelli uh from Synthesia and and and
Victor took a very uh kind of like
unusual approach to to build that
company. Um a number of rejections
actually until until Victor secured for
his company. uh and and really talked
about that insight that um ultimately
video generation needs to evolve very
similar to digital audio um from you
know modular layered components uh that
are remixable and this kind of like
guided the future of how Victor built
the the synthesia company. We started
the company back in 2017. Uh uh kind of
the AI winter type period at the time.
It wasn't uh it wasn't like the best
fundraising strategy uh to come uh and
come up with and you know today you're
this sort of you know sort of high-f
flyier. You know you I think you
announced that you're over 100 million
uh in ARR and you grew there like
massively fast and uh and that's
incredible. Uh but it didn't look like
that in the early years of it. Can you
tell us a little bit about just a bit of
an abbreviated story of the uh of the
early years? Uh
>> yeah, for sure. For sure. Um yeah, I
think in many ways I think we're a kind
of a a classical story of you know
looking looking like fools for three or
four years. Um but then you know
eventually turned out that that the kind
of bet we made back in 2017 we found the
company was uh was was right. But the
very brief story is that I I'm from co
Denmark like grew up there. um did a
bunch of things by myself. Worked in the
daily startup ecosystem. Uh knew that I
wanted to build a company. Knew I didn't
want to build like accounting tools um
and and kind of business process things.
I love science fiction.
>> You say you haven't. You sort of built
something a bit more creative than that.
Yeah.
Uh yeah. And and back then I was like
building like HR tools stuff. I was like
I learned a lot from it, right? I was
just like on a personal level. I love
sci-fi. I love Frontier Tech and I want
to do something that. So I moved to
London and I spent a year trying to
figure out like what I wanted to build.
This was just when AR and VR were kind
like in in in in kind of a hype cycle
since the Oculus had just came out and
everybody thought that by now we would
definitely all be in VR headsets all the
time. Um I I I love VR still to this
day, but I I kind of back then felt it's
it's not really there yet. Like there's
this just like there's like too many
obstacles. It's out of my control to
build a big company around it. And but I
met uh professor Matias Ner my
co-founder today who um had also looked
at VR but he' kind of looked at more of
the content creation angle and he' done
this this paper called face to face
which really was the first time the
world saw a neural network producing
photorealistic video frames
automatically. Um and this paper like
made quite a lot of quite a big big stir
and and and I saw it as well and I just
got obsessed with it. You know, I felt
like this is super early and of course
it, you know, it barely worked and we
look back today, it doesn't look very
impressive, but I just felt like
something very magical here, right? I
this is going to change first how we
create content, then it's going to
change content itself as we've just
discussed. And I just felt there was so
many parallels, you know, like uh I love
music. Music is my big passion when I'm
when I'm not working and especially
electronic music. Uh and I saw so many
parallels to how we, you know, like by
now like a lot of years ago, we started
to digitize how you make music, right?
You can sample things you're having to
use real estate. You can build
synthesizers. You can create sounds
yourself out of nothing, right? And
everything got brought to us in terms of
like new music genres, democratization
of access to music production and so on.
And it felt like, you know, what's
what's happening now is just that we're
digitizing um video, right? And there's
so many analogies to all the creative
music tools that we're using. So I got
very obsessed with that idea. By the
way, I didn't clue into that analogy.
that makes a lot of sense which you've
gone from whatever a physical guitar to
being able to reproduce that sound on uh
on the computer as an analogy to you
could produce a thing with a camera uh
and you know now you can generate that
on on screen. So doing a good job just
like I love that analogy.
>> Yeah, I think there's actually so much
of like um my experience like tinkering
around these tools uh in my in my in my
childhood that really you know it's one
of the things it's like in your back of
your head. you're not like consciously
thinking about all the time but
understanding how you make content
digitally I think was definitely helpful
anyway um we felt like you know let's
start trying to start a company around
this uh it took me a very long time to
convince Matias because at this point in
time I was 25 years old I had no I had
absolutely zero qualification to start
this company at all but I was just
obsessed with the idea y
>> and we managed to get a get kind of a
team together and we're trying to raise
some money totally impossible got turned
down by like 80 100 investors something
like that everybody just thought uh you
know the idea was kind of crazy which it
was like it it was you had to
extrapolate a lot to to see this
actually panning out but also at that
point in time especially in London there
like everybody wanted to fund like PhDs
right who would go out and they would
hire like the best free PhD friends and
they would like go on some journey to
create some big AI company and some of
those companies I think our strength
actually end up becoming the fact that
I'm not a PhD and that I'm a person
someone who thinks commercially but
people definitely didn't like that
>> at some point um my my co-founder
Stephan, he sends an email to Mark Cuban
cold. We found this email in a in a
leaked Sony hack. Um, and he sent a very
short email just saying, "Hey, we're
building this thing. We think you'd fit
very well. You know, he understands
technology, understand media." He
replies within three minutes. Very
interested. Sends a bunch of questions.
We email with him for 10 hours non-stop.
Never get on call with him. Um, and he
ends up investing a million dollars with
which which was the founder of the
company. And the lesson there was that
Mark had himself implemented the
face-to-face paper at home with a tutor.
He we did not have to convince him at
all that in 10 years time you can make a
Hollywood film with your laptop. He
completely bought into that. He was
essentially just evaluating the team,
right? Um and um and I think that was
like with if you're doing something
crazy, you want to try and find someone
who shares like your crazy vision of the
future because it's with VCs, right?
It's so hard to convince them something
they don't already believe. if it's not
like uh if it's if it's not like part of
the current dogma of like the tech
community.
>> Yeah. And the the VC world is very much
you only need to find one, but sometimes
you need to talk to so many. I mean,
>> exactly. The the Mark Cuban email is
like it's like a part of startup lore
now, you know, sort of sort of I've
heard that story now being told not by
you, you know, of people just sort of in
part is like they'll hold on sort of
faith on it. Uh and part sort of the
craze of it. But I guess what what I
don't know is like how many such emails
like the ones it's not that you sort of
picked hey the one person we're going to
email is Mark Cuban
>> I mean
definitely the hundreds maybe even in
the thousand right we were just
>> desperately trying to find someone to um
>> kind of help you get going on the
journey
>> and and I think you know looking back
like it's I understood why it was a
difficult pitch like I had no I was 25
years old had no qualification start the
company at all at least on paper. Um, it
was a crazy idea. It wasn't clear what
the real use case if the technology is
even going to work. Um, but I'm very
grateful that, you know, that Mark took
the bet on us. Um, and as it always is,
right, like raising money is like a is
is is a milestone, but the real hard
part began like after we got the money
and we're like, okay, great. So, no one
believes in us. We have a million
dollars. What can we realistically like
build and sell?
>> And this is what year is this? Like 2017
started the company. When are we now?
>> This is 17. So we we kind of
>> we kind of in spirit the idea originated
in 16 but we raised the first money uh
in in October 2017.
Um, and I think kind of like what we
what we essentially did when we found
the comrades, we did what you're
supposed to not do, which we bet on a
technology, not on a specific use case,
uh, or product, right? Um, and so we had
to kind of figure out, okay, what can we
build backwards from? So, we ended up in
this idea of like AI dubbing, which is
like you give us a real video, not a
generated video, we'll translate that to
a different language for you. Um, but
we'll not just replace the voice over,
but we'll also reanimate the face so it
looks like you're actually speaking in
like Spanish, Italian, whatever. And I
think the issue we had there was like,
you know, makes a lot of sense is like
you're an advertiser and if you live in
Europe, you've definitely seen like
really bad dopped ads, right? Where like
the mouths completely out of sync in the
German versions. If you can kind of know
for 10K or whatever can fix that for you
and all your ads look like they were
shot natively in whatever language that
you're put in, that makes sense. If
you're Netflix and you invest a lot of
money creating content and you could
take all those films, you can make them
look like they're actually shot natively
in German or French. that should have
some kind of like economical um there's
been economic things there, right?
>> I I love how this is a a European uh
pain point or a painoint felt more in
Europe on it. We had Mati on the from 11
Labs on the uh on the podcast as well
and they also a bunch of years later
started uh in that pain. I think it was
just a you feel it more closely when you
live in a in a non-S single language
ecosystem compared to the
>> very interesting because like the first
the first two funding rounds were were
very very very difficult um
>> not just because of this but it was
definitely also a thing that like the
American VC ecosystem didn't understand
the pain right they kind of like you
could explain to the yeah I kind of
guess that makes sense but you haven't
actually felt it firsthand or like you
know if you're a company and you're kind
of trying to penetrate many different
markets uh it's actually really hard
right and it's big value proposition of
the platform today like it is for for 11
labs. But but essentially that was the
thesis. We we built this thing. This is
back when you know this is like GANs
were like the thing back then. The
technology basically it did work if you
look straight at the camera without
looking away. And we had two PhDs
sitting for like two weeks to create a
30 secondond clip. So it was more kind
of like a visual effects we were all
kind of like a visual effects um you
know studio with a proprietary
technology. Um, and after having done it
for a few years, we did we did a million
dollars in revenue like that. Um, which
is which is not terrible at our stage,
right? It kept us alive. But it was very
clear to us that first of all, what
we're building was a painkiller. So, it
was a vitamin, not a painkiller. Um,
people thought it was like cool, but no
one would like scream and yell if we
disappeared the day after, right?